Hello friends, I am your personal
finance coach author. In today's video, we will
learn about a very good health insurance plan of ICC Lombard, Health and Advantage. Today we
will review it, decode this plan and
find out why this plan is so special.
If you are looking for a good family health
insurance plan or
a maternity plan, then this
plan is an ideal insurance policy for you.
So stay tuned with this video.
Let's start
friends. ICC Lombard is
one of the leading general insurance companies in India whose
claim settlement is very good. After
sales services are also very good.
If we talk about the features of this plan, then in this
we get worldwide care, consultation,
tech care, domestic and ambulance service, surface
ambulance service, home care treatment,
claim protector,
vaccine discount. Apart from this, many
value added services like video consultation,
consultation, medicine, pharmacy and
diagnostic services, online chat with
doctor, doctor on call and health assistant
services. The eligibility criteria for this
plan is minimum 18 years for the
individual.  For dependent children, the
entry period is 91 days, which means they can stay
in the family floater plan till they turn 25 years,
after that they will have to
shift to an individual policy. The maximum entry
period for this plan is 65 years.
Talking about exit, there is no exit option ahead.
You get the option of live long renewal. The
dependent child is
relieved to shift to the family floater or individual plan after turning 25. If we
talk about the proposal, the minimum policy term is 18
years. Policy term of 1, 2 and
3 years are available in this plan. In this plan, we have
both individual and family floater options
available, in which you can be an adult,
grand mother, father, in-law, mother, in-law, father, mother, spouse, son, daughter, son, in-law, daughter, in-law, grandson, granddaughter, brother, sister, in-law,
brother,
relationship etc. Talking about the benefits of this plan,
for sum injured,
we have options ranging from five crores to three crores, in
which  Inpatient care, tourist
surgery and AYUSH treatment are available.
Talking about inpatient treatment, friends,
we can provide injured inpatient treatment. If we
talk about hospital accommodation or room, then
other category rooms are available which are up to
F2.
Ayurveda, Yoga, Unani, Siddha,
Homeopathy are such alternative treatments
which are done before we go to the hospital. There are treatments
related to this disease.
In this plan, there is a
charge of 60 days for free hospital. Similarly,
even after discharge from the hospital, there are some of
our medicines and expenses which will be up to
180 days. In this plan, the
care procedures are such procedures
which due to technology are not just a few hours'
procedure, in these, there is no need for a full 24
hours or more hospital.
Such treatments and procedures are available.
A very good benefit of Islam in the policy is that it includes
organ donors.
Friends, in
case of transplant, there are very high medical
expenses on organ donors
in this plan.  Data, now you are giving us a shot.
Talking about other benefits,
in this plan,
we will get a maximum of 1%
for surface ambulance and road ambulance. Apart from this,
we also get a charge of ₹10,000 for animal white vaccination.
Talking about restore benefit,
we
know it by many names like restore, reinstatement, and full recharge. In which even
after our basic sum injured is exhausted, the
health insurance company recharges our policy for
further
hospitalization. In this policy,
friends, in this plan, a restore benefit equal to 100% of the basic sum
injured will be
available, which will become
active after partial utilization of our sum,
meaning we do
not need to consume the entire amount to restore it. The
restore benefit will be available to us after the first claim itself.
In this plan,
we do not get any no-claim bonus,
instead we get a guaranteed humorous
bonus, which will be shown at a maximum of 20% off time.
You get 100% Apart from this, in a plane,
we get the option of free health checkup
from the first flight, in which 0.5
percent maximum charges up to 10000 will be
available, which will be
on cashless basis. Apart from this, domestic
hospitalizations are
such hospitalizations which we get done
at home, suppose the condition of a patient
is so critical that he
cannot be admitted to any hospital
or he has to sit in a nearby hospital,
and in such a case, if we get hospitalization done at home, then it will
come under the category of domestic hospital. Talking about trick surgery,
friends, in this plane, 50%
maximum
surgeries are such surgeries which we get done for obesity or
motor vehicle related diseases,
apart from this, we
get a benefit which is 20000. If
our hospitalization is for more than 10 days, then
in such a case, one time 20000 charges are table.
Apart from this, in this plane, we get
tax for domestic and ambulance,
which will be longer than our basic semester,
meaning apart from our semester, we get
separate domestic and ambulance charges.
Apart from this, if there is a policy of more than 25 lakhs,
we also get the option of worldwide tax.
Friends, in this plan, we
also get the benefit of ambulance assistant.
If we are ever hospitalized, we have to be
shifted from a hospital or admitted
to a hospital and
if we are facing difficulty in connecting an ambulance, then
we can avail this benefit.
Apart from this, charges for consultation and home
treatment are available.
5% off time shoot maximum up
to 25000 will be available for home treatment.
Friends, home care treatment means that if the
doctor has suggested that we
can take that treatment at home, then such treatments
come under home care treatment.
Sometimes there are some types of therapies or
dialysis or hemotherapy, these types of
treatments which we
can also take at home, so such treatments
come under the category of home care treatment.
Talking about the optional benefits of this plan, the
biggest advantage of this plan or what should be
said, the biggest advantage of this plan is
maternity tax.  Maternity benefit which
will be available for a maximum of 10 months, friends, for this there is a
waiting period of only 12 months. In most of the
maternity plans, a waiting period of two years,
three years or even 12 years is
applicable, but
in this plan, you can cover your delivery expenses only after a waiting period of 9 months,
for which you have to pay a front premium of 3 months.
For maternity benefit, 10% off basic sum assured, up
to a maximum of 10 lakhs will be
available. For new born baby benefit,
if you have a policy of 10 lakhs, then
₹1 lakh will be available to you for maternity
and up
to ₹200000 will be available to you for newborn baby benefit.
Apart from this, if we talk about first birth vaccination, then
1% off
maximum up to 10000 charges will be available for
first birth vaccination for new born child.
For friends, the
newborn baby care and vaccination care is
a part of the maternity benefit.
Talking about other optional benefits, in this
we get an optional rider of critical illness in
which we get lump sum benefit equal to the
basic summation maximum
charge table of Rs 50 lakh if ​​any of the listed
criticalities are detected.
Apart from this, personal accident care is available in
which there will be accidental death, permanent total
disability and permanent partial disability care.
In case of accidental death, now we will have basic charge
tables up to Rs 50 lakh. For permanent and partial
disability, there will be
40 tables according to the security of disability, which is the
maximum
protector rider available in which
we have relief according to the consumer price
index, that is, the inflation of our country.
Relief is adjusted according to inflation. Relief increases little by little every year
as our inflation goes up.
Apart from this, we get another rider of accident
protector, friends, many  There are
consumable or non-medical items for
which health insurance does not charge.
If we take this rider, then
all our charges are taxable, which
come in the list of consumables, such as P
Kids Gloves Series Cotton. Friends, if we
talk about the waiting periods of this plan, then a waiting period of
2 years will be applicable for pre-existing diseases. For
specific
conditions, which we also call slow-growing diseases, a
waiting period of 2 years will be applicable for them,
such as cataract
hernia replacement. For these types of
treatments, a
waiting period of 2 years is applicable because
these diseases do not require immediate treatment. A
waiting period of 3 years will be applicable for battery treatment. The
initial waiting period will be 30 days.
For critical cases,
we have 60-day and 90-day options available for waiting period.
For critical cases, the survival
period is zero days. Friends, many
policies  The critical riders in this have
a survival period, which means that
if a critical condition is occurring, then
you must survive till that survival period.
If the
patient dies before the survival period, then
he does not get the benefit. There is a
zero discrepancy survival period in this plan, which means
this is a very good benefit.
Friends, in this plan we get
to see zone wise premium which is
divided into three zones. Zone One, which includes Daily NCR,
apart from that, Faridabad, Gurugram, New Rohtak,
Sonipat, Rewari, Jhajjar, Gurugram, Panipat, Palwal, Bhiwani,
Charkhi Dadri, Mahendragarh, Jind, Karnal,
Meer, Ghaziabad, Noida, Gautam Buddha Nagar,
Bulandshahr, Bagpat, Hapur, Shamli, Muzaffarnagar,
Thursday, Bharatpur and apart from that, whatever
NCT is Delhi, Mumbai, Thane, District, Navi Mumbai,
Gujarat, Kolkata, all these will
come in Zone One. Zone Two includes Hyderabad, Secunderabad,
Madhya Pradesh, Daman, Diu, Dadar Nagar Haveli, Goa,
Maharashtra, Exclusive Mumbai and Thane, Navi
Mumbai, all these will come in Zone One and apart from this,
Rest of Indian Zone
Friends, the premium of John One will be charged from John Two and the
premium of John 2 will be charged from John Three.
If we pay the premium of John 3 and go for
treatment in John 2 or John One, then
we have to pay that payment.
Similarly, if we pay the premium of John Two and go for
treatment in John One, then also we have to pay some
payment. If we have paid the premium of John One,
then we
can also get treatment done in Alwar, India
without payment. You should keep this thing in
mind at all. Apart from this, we get a
free look period of 15 days. If you have
taken the policy and you do not like the terms and conditions of the policy, then
you can
cancel your policy within 15 days and get this entire
money refunded. Apart from this, we have the
option of lifetime renewal in the policy.
In the policy, we have the options of 1 year, 2 years and 3 years. There is
no season ahead. There is an option of lifetime renewal in the policy.
If we
pay annual premium in this policy, then if we pay 30 days and monthly,
quarterly or half premium, then
There is a grace period of 15 days, which
means that if we forget to pay our premium
or are unable to pay it on time, then
we get a grace period of 15 days and 30 days.
Talking about discounts,
friends, in this we get a multi-year
discount. If we
take a policy for two years together, then we get a discount of 7.5% and
on taking a policy for three years together,
we get a discount of 10%. Apart from this, there is a
soft copy discount of ₹100 if we
take our policy in soft copy instead of hard copy. Friends, if you are looking for
a good health insurance for your family, then
this is a very good
insurance in which you
also get the additional benefit of maternity. If you
want to take a maternity policy, then you will have to
pay an apprentice premium of 3 years and
only a waiting period of 9 months will be
applicable in it. Friends,
if you have any doubt related to this plan, then you
can ask by commenting below. If you
liked this video and you
want to support our work, then you can buy this policy on
our website.  You can make a purchase with Saathi where we
recommend the right product according to your financial and medical condition.
Also, at the time of claim, one of our dedicated
teams guides you completely and helps you
in getting your claim. Friends, if you liked the
video then do like it and
subscribe to the channel. See you
in the next video. Thank you.